A Guide to the Papers of Floyd E. Johnson 1938-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Architectural Drawings, Sketches, Artwork, Awards, and Diplomas 1930-1998
  - Architectural Drawings 1930-1995, n.d., 6 items (Oversize 29)
    some mounted on boards - White Hall Farm, Gloucester, Virginia; Survey of Revolutionary War Cemetary, Williamsburg, Virginia; President's House, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia; Woodberry Forest School Auditorium
  - Architectural Drawings 1985-1986, n.d., 14 items (Oversize 30)
    some mounted on boards - University of Virginia; Miller Center of Public Affairs; Clinch Valley College Academic Building; Newcomb Hall; Facsimile of Academic Village consisting of the Lawn and Rotunda Drawing by Jefferson; East Range
  - Architectural Drawings 1938, n.d., 18 items (Oversize 31)
    Albemarle County Courthouse
  - Architectural Drawings 1979, 1989-1996, n.d., 30 items (Oversize 32)
    Belle Grove, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. E. Sykes Scherman
  - Architectural Drawings 1989, n.d., 12 items (Oversize 33)
    Brookwood School, Thomasville, Georgia
  - Architectural Drawings 1988-1989, 7 items (Oversize 34)
    Residence of William Buchardt, Post Oak, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1987-1997, n.d., 60 items including next folder (Oversize 35)
    Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Watson
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1987-1997, n.d. (Oversize 36)
  - Architectural Drawings 1961, n.d., 40 items (Oversize 37)
    Charlottesville Courthouse and Charlottesville Downtown Street Grid
  - Architectural Drawings 1949-1950, n.d., 20 items (Oversize 38)
    Cherry Hill, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Alonzo Rinehart
  - Architectural Drawings 1953-1992, n.d., 27 items (Oversize 39)
    Alterations and Additions to Christ Church, Glendower, Albemarle County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1960, n.d., 4 items (Oversize 40)
    Chub Cay House and Hotel, The Berry's Island Group, Bahamas
  - Architectural Drawings 1981-1995, n.d., 26 items (Box 41)
    Cismont Manor, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Wheeler
  - Architectural Drawings 1968, 2 items (Oversize 42)
    Derwent, Powhatan County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1987-1988, 5 items (Oversize 43)
    Echo Brook Farm, Keswick, Virginia, for Mrs. Gray McCarroll
  - Architectural Drawings 1988-1993, 45 items (Oversize 44)
    Residence [Sherwood Hill?] for Mr. and Mrs. Robert Frazier, Harrisonburg, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings, 4 items (Oversize 45)
    Proposed Motor Court for Mr. W.W. Fuller, Albemarle County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1989, 1993, 5 items (Oversize 46)
    Shed and Farm Building for Mr. and Mrs. Wayne Gibbens, Fauquier County
  - Architectural Drawings 1987-1992, 35 items (Oversize 47)
    Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Arthur A. Watson
  - Architectural Drawings 1987-1992, 31 items (Oversize 48)
  - Architectural Drawings 1968-1980, n.d., 42 items (Oversize 49)
    Glendower, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Alfred E. Jackson
  - Architectural Drawings 1969-1970, 8 items (Oversize 50)
  - Architectural Drawings 1983-1987, 30 items (Oversize 51)
    Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Joseph H. Hennage, Williamsburg, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1972-1995, n.d., 19 items (Oversize 52)
    Miscellaneous: including Hatton Ferry, Scottsville, Virginia; The Hermitage, Buckingham County, Virginia, for James L. Brown; The Horseshoe, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mrs. Harold B. Alexander; Ingleside Farm Residence for Bill and Jana Crutchfield, Albemarle County, Virginia; Indian Trace Farm, Locust Dale, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Stephen Murhpy; and Bench for Jackson Park, Charlottesville
  - Architectural Drawings 1991, 16 (Oversize 53)
    Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Alex Janssen, Albemarle County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1972-1991, 4 items (Oversize 54)
    Addition to Jefferson Mill, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. James L. Camp; and Residence for Mr. and Mrs. K.K. Knickerbocker, Ednam Village, Charlottesville, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1960, 1983, n.d., 15 items (Oversize 55)
    Jefferson-Madison Regional Library Alterations
  - Architectural Drawings 1990-1992, 6 items (Oversize 56)
    Residence for Mr. and Mrs. James H.T. McConnell, Jr., Orange County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1992-1993, 20 items (Oversize 57)
    Alterations and Additions to the McIntyre Library for the Albemarle County Historical Society, Charlottesville, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1942-1967, 57 items (Oversize 58)
    Mill House Alterations and Additions, for Mr. and Mrs. Floyd Johnson, Scottsville, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1971, 1976, n.d., 3 items (Oversize 59)
    Madison County Courthouse
  - Architectural Drawings 1993-1994, 50 items (Oversize 60)
    Mirador Kennel, Greenwood, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Paul Burghardt
  - Architectural Drawings 1993-1994, 34 items (Oversize 61)
  - Architectural Drawings 1993-1994, 16 items (Oversize 62)
  - Architectural Drawings 1986, 20 items (Oversize 63)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - reconstruction drawings
  - Architectural Drawings 1986, n.d., 36 items (Oversize 64)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - reconstruction drawings, first version, etc.
  - Architectural Drawings 1983-1986, n.d., 32 items (Oversize 65)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Visitor's Center Alterations and Additions
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1938-1960, n.d., 30 items (Oversize 66)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - House, including drawings by Milton Grigg
  - Architectural Drawings 1970-1973, n.d., 23 items (Oversize 67)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - House and Facilities and Air Conditioning Renovation, including drawings by Ballou and Justice
  - Architectural Drawings 1938-1989, 33 items (Oversize 68)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - House and Dome Room Oculus and Windows
  - Architectural Drawings 1949-1993, n.d., 30 items (Oversize 69)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Visitor's Center, Gift Shop, and Entrance Building (Copies of Drawings done by Milton Grigg)
  - Architectural Drawings 1940-1980 (Oversize 70)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Garden Pavilion, Topographic Map, Survey of First Roundabout, Contour Map of Tract, Walk Lighting, and Garden Diagram
  - Architectural Drawings 1981-1982, 30 items (Oversize 71)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Garden Pavilion
  - Architectural Drawings 1977, 22 items (Oversize 72)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Kurt Gloeckner Surveys
  - Architectural Drawings 1958, 1981-1990, 26 items (Oversize 73)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Mulberry Row, Levy Cemetary, Kelso Archaeological Plan and Gloeckner Survey, Stone Outhouse Restoration
  - Architectural Drawings 1986-1990, 13 items (Oversize 74)
    Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Historica Plant Center, Details of Garden Steps and Railings
  - Architectural Drawings 1996-1997, 24 items (Oversize 75)
    Mount Ida Restoration and Additions, Albemarle County, Virginia, for James B. Murray, Jr.
  - Architectural Drawings 1940-1990, 11 items (Oversize 76)
    Miscellaneous; including Rendering of Proposed Humpback Rocks Lodge and Food Country Store; Topographical Map of Layfayette Hill Tavern owned by Mr. and Mrs. John Graham, Fluvanna County, Virginia; Montpelier Viewing Stand, Orange County, Virginia; Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Gordon W. Poindexter, Jr. Waynesboro, Virginia; Amvest Corporation; Residence for Mr. and Mrs. james F. Lewis, Albemarle County, Virginia; Garage for W. H. Faulconer, Scottsville, Virginia; and Lanigan and Associates, Thomasville, Georgia, Office Addition
  - Architectural Drawings 1940-1995, 13 items (Oversize 77)
    Miscellaneous: including Tallwood, Albemarle Country, Virginia; Scottsville Museum, Albemarle County, Virginia; Tri-County Riding Club Porch Enclosure, Albemarle County, Virginia; Residence for Edward B. Wilkins, Charlottesville, Virginia; and Addition No. 3 to Computer Office Building, Virginia National Bank, Charlottesville, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1986-1987, 12 items (Oversize 78)
    Additions and Alterations to Long Branch, Millwood, Clarke County, Virginia, for Harry Z. Isaacs and [Caj?] Haakausson
  - Architectural Drawings 1983-1986, 30 items (Oversize 79)
    Old Town Farm, Point Pleasant, West Virginia, for Charles C. Lewis
  - Architectural Drawings 1996, 25 items (Oversize 80)
    St. Luke's Episcopal Church, Powhatan County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1952-1959, n.d., 14 items (Oversize 81)
    Shadwell Restoration, Albemarle County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1974-1975, 4 items (Oversize 82)
    Western Virginia Bicentennial Information Center, Albemarle County, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1994-1995, 18 items (Oversize 83)
    White Hall Farm, Gloucester, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Peter Hunt
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1940-1990, 27 items (Oversize 84)
    Miscellaneous: Details, including Memorial for Mary Stuart Johnson; Land Plats; and Unidentified
  - Architectural Drawings, 11 items (Oversize 85)
    Miscellaneous Charcoal and Pastel Drawings
  - Architectural Drawings 1995, n.d., 48 items (Oversize 86)
    Miscellaneous Working Sketches and Design Schemes on Trace Paper
  - Architectural Drawings 1968-1970, 19 items (Oversize 87)
    Glendower, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Dr. and Mrs. A.E. Jackson
  - Architectural Drawings 1985-1986, 50 items (Oversize 88)
    Hennage House, Williamsburg, Virginia, Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Joseph H. Hennage
  - Architectural Drawings 1993, 2 items (Oversize 89)
    Mirador, Greenwood, Albemarle County, Virginia, Topographical Map of Area around House and Barn for Riding Ring for Paul Burghardt by Gloeckner and Osborne
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1959-1974, n.d., 10 items (Oversize 90)
    Monticello - Topographical Maps, etc.
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1953-1986, 23 items (Oversize 91)
    Monticello - House, Topographical Maps, etc
  - Architectural Drawings [1939?]-1995, 27 items (Oversize 92)
    Miscellaneous: Burning Daylight Farm Topographical Map and Training Stable; Charlotteville Fire House Liberty Bell Lighting Detail; Edgemont, Albemarle County, Virginia; Lanigan and Associates, Pineapple Detail, based on an example from Cherry Hill Farm; Piedmont Virginia Community College Topographical Map, Site Plans, etc; and Unidentified
  - Architectural Drawings 1970, 1981, n.d., 6 items (Oversize 93)
    Miscellaneous: Details for Memorial for Mary Stuart Johnson; Site Plan for Residence of W.A. Perkins, Jr., Deltaville, Virginia; Office Building for the State Capitol Area (Ballou and Justice)
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1953-1960, n.d., 37 items (Oversize 94)
    Shadwell Restoration, Albemarle County, Virginia, Site Plans, Archaeological Surveys, etc.
  - Architectural Drawings 1938-1939, 1971, 34 items (Oversize 95)
    University of Virginia - Rotunda Restoration and Adaptation by Ballou and Justice, Copies of Drawings by Stanislaw Makielski
  - Architectural Drawings 1983, 8 items (Oversize 96)
    University of Virginia - Rotunda Esplanade Deck Renovation
  - Architectural Drawings 1934-1986, 14 items (Oversize 97)
    University of Virginia - Administration Building (Madison Hall); Miller Center; the Garden Pavilions Restoration by the Garden Club of Virginia by Alden Hopkins, Landscape Architect
  - Architectural Drawings 1995, 35 items (Oversize 98)
  - Architectural Drawings 1994-1995, 11 items (Oversize 99)
  - Architectural Drawings 1935-1958, n.d., 8 items (Oversize 100)
    Colonial Williamsburg
  - Airport Terminal Building, Charlottesville, Virginia 1958 (Oversize 258)
  - Ednam Forest - Proposed Apartments (Oversize 258)
  - Joint Security Coplex for Charlottesville and Albemarle County 1971 (Oversize 258)
    South View
  - Hollymead Renovation (Oversize 258)
  - Scheme Number 5 for McIntyre House (Oversize 258)
  - Monticello - Proposed Curator's House 1970, 2 boards (Oversize 258)
  - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. H.L. Pettey 1954 (Oversize 259)
  - Piedmont Virginia Community College - Proposed Pool 1954 (Oversize 259)
  - Preliminary Study of Residence for Mr. and Mrs. John B. Rogan, Oakencroft Farm 1948 (Oversize 259)
  - Proposed Design for Saint James Church (Oversize 259)
  - Proposed Entrance Detail for State Farm Mutual Automobile Insurance Company 1950 (Oversize 259)
  - University of Virginia - Proposed Dormitories 1961, 2 boards (Oversize 259)
  - University of Virginia 1976-1977, 3 boards (Oversize 259)
    Administration Building - Madison Hall Site Plan, Section, and Elevation
  - Virginia National Bank (Oversize 259)
  - Western Virginia Bicentennial Center Aerial View 1975 (Oversize 259)